Now, let's see how to execute code with conditional statements in it.
现在，让我们看看如何执行包含条件语句的代码。
Here, we have a function f which has some if and if else statements.
在这里，我们有一个函数 f，它有一些 if 和 if else 语句。
As always, our program starts its execution at the beginning of main.
与往常一样，我们的程序从 main 的开头开始执行。
The first statement declares a variable a,
第一条语句声明了一个变量 a，
so we make a box for it.
所以我们为它做了一个方框。
Even though this statement initializes a,
尽管此语句初始化 a，
it's going to take us several steps to compute that value,
但计算该值需要几个步骤，
so we're going to leave a's value as a question mark
因此我们要将 a 的值留作问号，
until we compute the value of f of 3, 4.
直到我们计算 f 的值为 3、4。
To evaluate the call to f,
为了评估对 f 的调用，
we make a frame passing the values of the parameters.
我们制作一个传递参数值的帧。
We know where to return to and move the execution arrow to the first line of f.
我们知道在哪里返回并将执行箭头移到 f 的第一行。
The next line of code is an if statement whose conditional expression is x less than y.
下一行代码是条件表达式 x 小于 y 的 if 语句。
We evaluate that expression and find that three less than four is true,
我们计算该表达式后发现小于 4 的三个为真，
so we move the execution arrow into
因此我们将执行箭头移到
the then clause of this if statement and continue executing.
此 if 语句的 then 子句中并继续执行。
The next statement is a call to print f,
下一个语句是调用 print f
which you are familiar with.
，你很熟悉。
We write x less than y in our output.
我们在输出中写入 x 小于 y。
Next, we return y plus x.
接下来，我们返回 y 加 x。
This follows the same rules you have already learned for return statements.
这遵循的规则与你已经学过的 return 语句规则相同。
We evaluate the expression to get the return value which is seven.
我们评估表达式以得到返回值，即七。
This is what the function call will evaluate to.
这就是函数调用的计算结果。
And now, we return back to the caller,
现在，我们回到调用者身边，
destroying the frame for f. Now,
销毁 f 的帧。现在，
we are ready to finish initializing a since we know that
我们已经准备好完成初始化 a 了，因为我们知道
the call of f evaluated to seven.
f 的调用计算结果为 7。
So a is now seven.
所以 a 现在是七个。
We are now ready for the next line of code in main.
现在，我们已经为 main 中的下一行代码做好了准备。
We make a box for b and call f,
我们为 b 做一个方框然后调用 f，
passing in seven and five.
传入七和五。
We once again want to evaluate the condition,
我们再次想评估条件，
x less than y.
x 小于 y。
However, now, x is seven and y is five,
但是，现在 x 是七，y 是五，
so x less than five is false.
所以 x 小于 5 是假的。
We find the close curly brace for
我们找到
this if statement and see that the if statement has an else clause.
这个 if 语句的右大括号，看到 if 语句有一个 else 子句。
So we move the execution arrow into the start of
因此，我们将执行箭头移到
the else clause and continue executing from there.
else 子句的开头，然后从那里继续执行。
First, we execute the print statement,
首先，我们执行打印语句，
and then we reach another if statement.
然后到达另一个 if 语句。
This if statement is nested inside of the else,
这个 if 语句嵌套在 else
but that does not affect the rules of how we evaluate it.
中，但这并不影响我们如何评估它的规则。
We see that the conditional expression is false,
我们看到条件表达式为 false，
so we look for the close curly brace of the if statement.
因此我们寻找 if 语句的右大括号。
There is no else clause,
没有 else 子句，
so we move the execution arrow immediately past
因此我们立即将执行箭头移到右
the close curly brace and continue execution.
大括号上方，然后继续执行。el@@
There are no more statements inside the else clause,
se 子句中没有更多的语句，
so we move the execution arrow outside of the else clause and keep going.
所以我们将执行箭头移到 else 子句之外并继续前进。
Now, we have a return statement so we evaluate the expression, x minus two,
现在，我们有一个 return 语句，因此我们计算表达式 x 减二，
to find that the return value is five,
发现返回值为 5，
which will get returned to the place that we have noted.
该值将返回到我们注意到的位置。
We return back to the main and destroy the frame for f,
我们返回主节点并销毁 f 的框架，
then we finish the assignment statement.
然后我们完成赋值语句。
Now, we are at the return statement from main,
现在，我们在 main 的 return 语句处，
we execute that, and exit the program.
我们执行该语句，然后退出程序。